

# **CONTACT INFORMATION**

416-830-4792

chdshah@gmail.com

Toronto, ON

https://www.chitracodes.com/

## SUMMARY

Hello! I'm Chitra! I was raised in New Jersey, USA and have moved to Toronto to start this Developer journey. I bring over 8 years of corporate work experience which I believe makes a well rounded individual. I found my passion in Web Development while working with technology experts in my prior field of Immigration Law. I found that in communicating my needs to developers, I was getting frustrated with not being able to build the application myself. So this is my journey in doing exactly that!

## TECH SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

React

**Firebase** 

Git Version control

**VS** Code

**Bloomberg Terminal** 

**Excel (Pivot Tables & Pivot Reporting)** 

West Law & Nexis Lexis

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Best practices for modern web development
Website accessibility requirements
Presentation/Public Speaking
Legal Writing & Research
Immigration Law

### **PROJECTS**

TITLE	DESCRIPTION & LINK	TECHNOLOGIES USED
Tense Match	A simple matching game of verb tenses https://bit.ly/2Imw0eY	JavaScript(ES6), JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design
Are they working in?	App to identify whether current date is a working day or a national holiday in over 200 countries. https://bit.ly/2IUfzpk	React, Dom Manipulation, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design, Accessible Design.
Abbiocco	A vegan and vegetarian recipe generator. https://bit.ly/2MSSuZA	JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design, APIs, Accessible Design.
Superfoods Navigator	A nutrition facts generator. https://bit.ly/2MWjdo2	React, Firebase, API, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design, Accessible Design.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ANDIAMO, Toronto, CA 2018-2019

# TECHNOLOGY TALENT ACQUISITION SPECIALIST

 Conducted full life cycle recruitment of technology executives and professionals for tech firms and top financial institutions. e.g. Bloomberg, Amazon, HBO, Two Sigma, and more.

BLOOMBERG L.P. New York, USA | Toronto, CA 2017-2018

#### HR EXPERT-IMMIGRATION SPECIALIST

- Served as direct contact to 3000+ employees and various government agencies on behalf of Bloomberg LP.
- Partnered with HR Business Partners and Recruiting on complex immigration matters and provide strategic immigration/ mobility analysis.

GEP WORLDWIDE New Jersey, USA 2015-2017

# BUSINESS IMMIGRATION/GLOBAL MOBILITY SPECIALIST

- Single company wide point-of-contact for legal and immigration law related matters under direct supervision of General Counsel for global force of 2000+ employees.
- Provided guidance to senior management on all immigration related matters.

NPZ LAW GROUP, P.C. New Jersey, USA 2012-2015

#### IMMIGRATION PARALEGAL

- End to end preparation of petitions for filings before USCIS and direct consular filings at U.S. consulates abroad.
- SME for the law firm on DACA filings introduced in 2012 by President Obama.

## **EDUCATION**

Web Development Immersive (2019)

Accelerated Web Development Foundations/Advanced (2019)

American Bar Association Certified Paralegal Studies Program (2012)

Bachelor's Degree, Political Science (2010) HACKERYOU, COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY TORONTO, CANADA

HACKERYOU, COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY TORONTO, CANADA

FAIRLEIGH DICKINSON UNIVERSITY (USA)

RUTGERS, THE STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW JERSEY (USA)